Guide to the Sylvester Manor Archive 1649-1996 MSS 208
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Record Group VI: Photographic Material
  - Series B: Sylvester Manor, 27 Craigie Street, and Other Places
    - Negatives - "Gardiner Grave in New London and Cottage...at Cutchogue", undated (Box 125, Folder 23)
    - Negatives - "Harvest Festival", undated (Box 125, Folder 24)
    - Negatives - "Garden, Lovely, Clear", undated (Box 125, Folder 25)
    - Negatives - "All Peacock", 1817 (Box 125, Folder 26)
    - Negatives - "Best Garden", undated (Box 125, Folder 27)
    - Negative - bench in garden, 1916 (Box 125, Folder 28)
    - Negative - "Barns from Old Road - Not Good", "Sunlight from St. Kitts", undated (Box 125, Folder 29)
    - Negatives - Various Sylvester Manor garden images, undated (Box 125, Folder 30)
    - Negatives in a French Kodak package, circa 1900 (Box 125, Folder 31)
    - Negatives - Sylvester Manor gardens and grounds, undated (Box 125, Folder 32)
    - Film negatives - Gardening, Sylvester Manor and grounds, undated (Box 125, Folder 33)
  - Series C: Miscellaneous
    - Cornelia Horsford - "Prints of unidentified Scandinavian landscape" - photos from Iceland expedition, undated (Box 126, Folder 1)
    - Norumbega research materials - photographs with related letter, circa 1896 (Box 126, Folder 2)
    - Norumbega research photos - Cornelia Horsford (Box 126, Folder 3)
    - Photographs and drawings from Erlingsson expedition in Iceland, 1895 (Box 126, Folder 4)
    - Photos of Archaelogical dig, undated (Box 126, Folder 5)
    - Photo (mounted) - still life with urn, candle, fruit, undated (Box 126, Folder 6)
    - Photo (?) prints of angels, undated (Box 126, Folder 7)
    - Ship photos, circa 1958 (Box 126, Folder 8)
    - Photo of statue - Fiske - 1991 (Box 126, Folder 9)
    - Photo of Lion Gardiner statue, undated (Box 126, Folder 10)
    - Photograph of drawing of waterfront scene with envelope to Andrew Fiske, 1974 (Box 126, Folder 11)
    - Photo of painting - "Sylvester L'Hommedieu - aged 22 - From a portrait by Sir Benj. West", undated (Box 126, Folder 12)
    - Photo of a drawing of a windmill - Fiske, undated (Box 126, Folder 13)
    - Photocopy image of Richard Nicolls document, undated (Box 126, Folder 14)
    - Printed photos of documents related to War of 1812, undated (Box 126, Folder 15)
    - Photographs of 18th century documents, undated (Box 126, Folder 16)
    - Photo negatives of letters - William Floyd to Ezra L'Hommedieu (original date - 1783), undated (Box 126, Folder 17)
    - Fiske - photo negative - 19th century letter, undated (Box 126, Folder 18)
    - Photo negatives - Ezra L'Hommedieu and George Clinton Correspondence, undated (Box 126, Folder 19)
      See also - Box 2 Folders 43-45 for original Ezra L'Hommedieu/George Clinton correspondence.
    - Photo negatives - Joseph Henry correspondence with E.N.H. (orignal date - 1886), undated (Box 126, Folder 20)
    - Photo negatives of documents (original dates - 1780-1783 - Fiske [with photo envelope dated 1915-1916], 1955, undated (Box 126, Folder 21)
    - Photo negatives - painting of windmill, painting of Sylvester L''Hommedieu, old document, undated (Box 126, Folder 22)
    - Photo negative of boats - Fiske, undated (Box 126, Folder 23)
    - Bundle of miscellaneous photos - curled, undated (Box 126, Folder 24)
    - Bundle of miscellanous photos with note - "return to Mabel Tower" [tightly curled, inaccessible to researchers], undated (Box 127, Folder 1)
  - Series D: Albums (Flat)
    - Photo album - Fiske family, 1913-1915 (Box 134, Folder 1)
    - Photo album - Fiske family, circa 1910-1918 (Box 134, Folder 2)
    - Snapshot album - Sylvester Manor grounds, children, undated (Box 135, Folder 1)
    - Photo Album - travel, Sylvester Manor and Horsford family, undated (Box 135, Folder 2)
    - Sylvester Manor photo album [Historical Structure Report] (includes images from glass plate negatives), undated (Box 135, Folder 3)
    - Dark green Kodak photo album (Europe?), undated (Box 136, Folder 1)
    - Photo album - unknown people (possibly Mary Gardiner Horsford Fiske), undated (Box 136, Folder 2)
    - Sylvester Manor scrapbook - photos, art, documents, undated (circa 1870s-1910s) (Box 136, Folder 3)
  - Series E: Glass Plate Negatives and Slides (Odd size)
    - "No. N - Water Garden", undated (Box 137, Folder 1)
    - "No. K - Corner of Wood Road", undated (Box 137, Folder 2)
    - "No. 42 - Lilian and Sherman in the Golden Parrot", undated (Box 137, Folder 3)
    - "No. F - Lawn from Piazza", undated (Box 137, Folder 4)
    - "No. G - Poultry Yard Lane", undated (Box 137, Folder 5)
    - Unlabelled negative of garden [broken, fragment missing], undated (Box 137, Folder 6)
    - "No. J - Lower garden from poultry yard", undated (Box 137, Folder 7)
    - "No. O - Group by water garden", undated (Box 137, Folder 8)
    - "No. 35 - Dr. Storrs", undated (Box 137, Folder 9)
    - "No. 37 - Gog and Magog", undated (Box 137, Folder 10)
    - "No. 44 - View toward summer house", undated (Box 137, Folder 11)
    - Unlabelled negative of garden, undated (Box 137, Folder 12)
    - "Kate by Balustrade", undated (Box 137, Folder 13)
    - "No. I - Birch Tree in the Woods", undated (Box 137, Folder 14)
    - "No. 36 - Slave Burying Ground", undated (Box 137, Folder 15)
    - "No. U - Apple Tree and Hydrangeas", undated (Box 137, Folder 16)
    - "No. 41 - Mack in Box Path", undated (Box 137, Folder 17)
    - "No. 46 - Grass Path in Garden", undated (Box 137, Folder 18)
    - "No. 43 - Lotus and Willow" [blurred], undated (Box 137, Folder 19)
    - "No. 33 - Lawn Facing Creek" [broken, fragment missing], undated (Box 137, Folder 20)
    - "No. 34 - Fountain" [clouded], undated (Box 138, Folder 1)
    - "No. 40 - Fountain", undated (Box 138, Folder 2)
    - "No. W - Mac in Water Garden" [cracked], undated (Box 138, Folder 3)
    - "No. V - Manor House", undated (Box 138, Folder 4)
    - "No. T - Garden House and Steps", undated (Box 138, Folder 5)
    - "No. R - Piazza", undated (Box 138, Folder 6)
    - "No. Q - The Turn in the Wood Road Toward Woodstock", undated (Box 138, Folder 7)
    - Unlabelled negative of water garden, undated (Box 138, Folder 8)
    - "No. 45 - Big Willow and Gate", undated (Box 138, Folder 9)
    - "No. K - Terrace Steps with Lilies", undated (Box 138, Folder 10)
    - "No. M - House with Poplars", undated (Box 138, Folder 11)
    - "No. L - Manor Gate", undated (Box 138, Folder 12)
    - Glass Negative Holder #2 (glass present - no image), undated (Box 138, Folder 13)
    - Glass Negative Holder #12 (glass present - no image), undated (Box 138, Folder 14)
    - Glass negative envelopes, undated (Box 138, Folder 15)
    - Woman in front of fireplace, undated (Box 139, Folder 1)
    - Mamma, Papa, Mamie and Gertrude, undated (Box 139, Folder 2)
    - Color glass slide - woman at monument, undated (Box 139, Folder 3)
    - Color glass slide - Garden flowers, undated (Box 139, Folder 4)
    - Glass slide - garden path, undated (Box 139, Folder 5)
    - Glass negative envelope, undated (Box 139, Folder 6)
  - Photographic Material: Oversize
    - Oversize Series A: People and Portraits
      - Andrew Fiske as a boy (includes photo with Gertrude Horsford Fiske), circa 1917 (Box 132, Folder 1)
      - Two girls in garden (Sylvester Manor?), undated (Box 132, Folder 2)
      - Unknown portrait (priest or reverend?), undated (Box 132, Folder 3)
      - Photograph and reproductions of Ms. Sylvanus Reed, undated (Box 132, Folder 4)
      - Eben Norton Horsford portrait, undated (Box 132, Folder 5)
      - E.N. Horsford portrait photograph and engraving prints made from photo, undated (Box 132, Folder 6)
      - Engraving prints made from E.N. Horsford photograph 2 of 2, undated (Box 132, Folder 7)
      - Prints of painted portraits of Andrew Fiske and Gertrude Horsford Fiske, 1920, 1930 (Box 132, Folder 8)
      - Two portraits, unidentified women (one possibly Cornelia Horsford), undated (Box 132, Folder 9)
      - Photo - unknown individuals on Sylvester Manor portch (Cornelia Horsford, Gertrude and Andrew Fiske?), undated (Box 132, Folder 10)
      - Photograph of unknown woman and child, 1907 (Box 147, Folder 1)
      - Photograph of (Mary Gardiner Horsford?), undated (Box 152, Folder 26)
      - Photograph - Phebe Horsford, undated (Box 152, Folder 27)
    - Oversize Series B: Sylvester Manor, 27 Craigie Street, and Other Places
      - Photos of Sylvester Manor and grounds (some items damaged), undated (Box 133, Folder 1)
        treated for mold 7/06
      - Photographic print of Sylvester Manor front lawn towards inlet - "H.D. Bastow, Jamaica, L.I.", undated (Box 133, Folder 2)
      - Photos of Sylvester Manor and grounds, Gardiner's Island, undated (Box 133, Folder 3)
      - Photograph of Albany Female Academy, undated (Box 133, Folder 4)
      - Photographs - Sylvester Manor grounds with notes, undated (Box 133, Folder 5)
      - Photographs - Quaker Burial Ground Memorial dedication, undated (Box 133, Folder 6)
      - Photographic prints of Sylvester Manor grounds 1 of 2, undated (Box 133, Folder 7)
      - Photographic prints of Sylvester Manor grounds 2 of 2, undated (Box 133, Folder 8)
      - Sylvester Manor and 27 Craigie Street - photos, undated (Box 133, Folder 9)
      - Sylvester Manor and grounds [Historic Structure report photos], undated (Box 133, Folder 10)
      - Photos relating to Henry W. Longfellow, undated (Box 133, Folder 11)
      - Harbor at Brook Point, 1870 (Box 147, Folder 2)
      - Photos - unknown church (1 colorized), undated (Box 147, Folder 3)
        Treated for mold 7/2006
      - Photo - Unknown House, undated (Box 147, Folder 4)
      - Photos - Railroad scenes (1 of Toltec Tunnel), undated (Box 147, Folder 5)
    - Oversize Series C: Miscellaneous
      - Photos removed from "Reports, dig plans and photographs re Icelandic expedition and archaelogic sites in Cambridge", circa 1896 (Box 133, Folder 12)
      - Photograph of silver plate from Sylvesters, notes on reverse, 1884 (Box 147, Folder 6)
- Record Group VII: Artifacts
  This record group contains a small number of trunks, document boxes, and letter files and wallets which stored documents and photographs in the collection.
  - Metal lockbox belonging to Andrew Fiske, undated (Box 156)
  - Metal lockbox, letter satchels, small frames, cigar box with ship records, metal writing implements, undated (Box 157)
    Metal writing implements removed from Box 107 Folder 25.
  - Letter wallets, file folders, empty boxes that housed letters and negatives., undated (Box 158)
  - Large boards that contained large maps, engravings, and other items., undated (Box 159)